Medbh McGuckian papers, 1964-2006
Emory University
- Unprocessed additions, Series 7; Boxes 74-78
  - Notebooks (Box 78)
GALLAGHER, TESS 1977 February 1, TLS, 2pps 1977 March 23, ALS, 7pps w/ envelope 1977 April 7, ALS, 6pps w/ envelope 1977 May 7, APS 1977 May 29, TLS, 5pps w/ poems "Under Stars" and "The Sky Behind It" 1977 July 8, APS 1977 July 15, ALS, 6pps w/ envelope 1977 August 20, ANS w/ envelope 1982 August 21, TL (1p) and ALS (2pps) w/ envelope 1982 October 20, ALS, 1p 1983 January 24, TLS, 2pps w/ envelope 1984 July 4, ALS, 1p w/ 4 pp of poetry, poems: "All Day the Light is Clear," "In Maceio," "Her Walking" 1985 January 30, TLS, 2pps 1985 March, ANS with article, 2pps 1986 February 5, ALS, 1p w/ envelope 1987 June 14, ANS 1986 July 16, ALS, 4pps w/ envelope 1987 June 14, 1p 1987 November 11, 4pps w/ envelope 1988 April 14, ALS, 6pps 1988 June 26, ACS w/ envelope 1990 August 8, TLS, 2pps 1991 January 1, ACS w/ envelope 1991 April 8, 3pps 1991 May 7, TLS, 1p 1991 May 10, TLS,1p w/ envelope 1991 May 23, 3pps with Poem, "The Turning," 23 May 1991 1992 May 9, TLS, 1p 1992 June 6, 2pps 1993 February, TLS, 2pps w/ envelope 1993 February 21, TLS, 1p w/ envelope and enclosure 1993 March 9, TLS, 2pps w/ enclosure 1993 June 12, TLS, 1p 1993 October 14, TLS, 2pps w/ envelope 1994 June 22, TLS, 1p w/ envelope and enclosure 1994 August 8, TLS, 2pps w/ envelope 1994 October 26, TLS, 2pps w/ envelope 1994 September 20, TLS, 1p w/ envelope 1995 May 23, 1p w/ envelope 1995 July 26, photograph, 26 July 1996 January 4, Christmas card w/ envelope 1996 March 31, 1p w/ poem "Daffodils" 1996 June 7, post card undated, ANS w/ 4pps, poem "Amplitude" undated, ALS, 1p undated, ALS, 7 pp undated, ALS, 1p undated, ACS
GRENNAN, EAMON 1985 November 22, 1p w/ Table of contents for Verse
GROARKE, VONA 2001 September 3, post card w/ envelope
HARRISON, TONY 1991 August 8, post card
HEANEY, MARIE [RESTRICTED] 1990 November 8, ACS 1992 October 13, ACS 1993 January 10, 1p 1999 January 12, 1p 1999 March 25, 1p 2000 August 2, ANS w/ envelope 2000 September 9, ACS w/ envelope 2000 October 23, APS undated, AN on promotional item undated, ACS undated, APS undated, APS
HEANEY, SEAMUS [RESTRICTED] 1985 October 24, ALS, 1p w/ envelope 1988 September 12, ALS, 1p w/ envelope and poem "Composed for Harvard's 250th Anniversary" 1989 April 5, ALS, 1p 1989 November 6, TLS [copy] [Diane Der Hovanessian to SH] 1991 January 15, ANS on untitled prose work about contemporary Irish poets, 4pps w/ envelope 1991 January 28, ALS, 1p w/ envelope 1993 July 30, ALS, 1p w/ envelope 1993 November 15, ACS w/ envelope 1996 March 25, 1p w/ envelope 1996 April 6, 2pps w/ envelope 1996 October 3, 1p w/ envelope 1996 December, Christmas card 1997 December 11, TLS, 2pps w/ envelope 1997 December, Christmas card 1998 February 18, 2pps w/ envelope 1998 March 4, ALS, 2pps w/ envelope and poem "A Brigid's Girdle" 1998 July 25, TLS, addressed to Sophie and Eunan, 1p 1999 April 8, APS w/ envelope 2000 January 21, ALS from McGuckian to Heaney, 1p [see Faxes from McGuckian] 2004 December 22, ACS w/ envelope 2005 January 28, APS 2006 March 15, APS 2006 April 19, ACS w/ envelope 2006 October 2, ALS, 1p w/ envelope 2006 October 10, ALS 1p w/ envelope 2006 October 30, ALS, 1p w/ envelope undated, 2pps undated, ALS from McGuckian to Heaney, 1p [See Undated correspondence by indexed people] undated, ALS from McGuckian to Heaney, 1p [See Undated correspondence by indexed people] undated, ALS from McGuckian to Heaney, 1p [See Undated correspondence by indexed people]
HIGGINS, RITA ANN 1987 May 30, ALS, 3pps 1987 August 5, ALS, 3pps w/ enclosures: O'Donnell O'Hara to RH, TLS [copy], 1 p, with 2 articles and poem "A Traveller's Poem" 1988 October 5, ACS w/ photograph and envelope 1989 March 4, ALS w/ envelope 1989 July 25, ACS 1989 September 8, ALS, 1p 1990 January 12, ALS, 2pps 1990 May 28, ACS 1991 January 2, ANS 1992 April 24, envelope with curriculum vitae 1995 December 20, Christmas card undated, ALS, 3pps undated, ACS undated, Christmas card undated, 2pps
HUGHES, TED 1994 February 15, TLS [copy], 1p w/ 6pps of attachments 1996 January 15, 1p
JOHNSTON, JENNIFER 1990 September 11, ACS 1990, ACS 1993 December 3, ACS undated, ALS, 1p undated, ALS, 1p undated, ACS undated, ALS, 1p undated, ALS, 1p undated, ALS, 1p undated, ALS, 1p undated, ACS undated, ALS, 1p w/ envelope and poems, "Tracings," "Standings," "The First November," "Sky on West Springfield," "It Hurts so Good," "Immigrants,""“The Friend,” “Early Morning,” “Thoughts on a Photograph”
LARKIN, PHILIP 1982 November, 1p
LEVERTOV, DENISE undated, ANS
LONGLEY, EDNA 1985 May 14, ALS, 1p 1990 October 9, 1p 1991 August 12, 1p 1993 December 12, 1p 1994 September 29, ACS 1995 March 29, ALS, 1p 1995 May 2, TLS, 1p w/ envelope 1998 November 24, ALS, 1p 2001 January 23, ALS, 1p w/ envelope 2001 August 1, ALS, 1p undated, post card undated, ALS, 1p
LONGLEY, MICHAEL 1979 December 18, ACS 1980 May 21, ACS 1982 June 7,1p [See Arts Council Subject File] 1982 October 1, 1p [See Arts Council Subject File] 1983 April 11, 1p [See Arts Council Subject File] 1983 October 7, 1p [See Arts Council Subject File] 1983 October 17, 1p [See Arts Council Subject File] 1983 November 9, ALS, 1p w/ 2pps attachment [See Arts Council Subject File] 1984 March 13, 1p w/ envelope 1984 March 22, TLS, 1p w/ 1p attachment [See Arts Council Subject File] 1985 April 12, TLS, 1p w/ 2pps attachment [See Arts Council Subject File] 1986 January 21, 1p 1986 March 13, ALS, 1p w/ envelope 1987 July 29, TLS, 1p 1989 June 27, ALS, 1p w/ envelope 1989 August 29, ANS 1997 October 24 1997 December, Christmas card 1999 October 26, TLS, 2pps 1999 December 29, Christmas card w/ envelope w/ poem "The Lizard" 2002, Christmas card w/ poem "Praxilla" 2005 January 25, TLS 1p w/ envelope 2005, Christmas card w/ poem "Marsh Cinquefoil" undated, ACS undated, ALS, 1p undated, ALS, 1p undated, ACS undated, ACS undated, ACS undated, ACS undated, ALS, 1p undated, Christmas card
MAHON, DEREK 1983 May 24, ACS 1987 May 23, ACS
MACINTYRE, TOM 1989 August 20, ANS with poem "Shaper" 1993 November 5, ANS
MCBREEN, JOAN 1988 December 16, 4pps 1989 March 8, 4pps 1989 March 20,1p 1989 April 11, 3pps w/ envelope 1989 April 24, 1p with card and envelope 1989 July 20, 1p 1989 August 10, card 1989 August 23, card 1989 August 31, post card 1989 September 20, 1p with post card 1989 October 25, post card 1989 November 20, 1p 1989 December 11, 1p 1989, Christmas card 1990 January 15, 1p 1990 March 22, card 1990 April 10, 2pps w/ envelope 1990 June 6,card w/ 1p 1990 June 25, card 1990 August 1, post card 1990 October 2, post card 1990 October 29, post card 1990 November 19, post card 1991 April 30, post card 1991 May 7, post card 1991 May 14, post card 1991 June 10, card 1991 July 15, card 1991 September 10, post card 1991 September 16, 1p with review of JM's The Wind Beyond the Wall and envelope 1991 October 21, card 1991 November 20, post card 1992 January 14, card 1992 February 10, card 1992 February 25, card 1992 March 13, 1p w/ 2pps of poetry; Poems: "In the Iris Garden" and "On Reading your Letter in June" 1992 April 16, card with 1p of poetry and envelope; Poem: "The Swan" 1992 July 26, post card 1992 September 7, card 1992 September 20, post card 1992 September 21, 1p 1992 October 10, post card 1992 October 19, two post cards 1992 December 17, Christmas card 1992 December 29, post card 1993 January 13, post card 1993 January 25, card 1993 January 29, post card 1993 February 16, card 1993 April 5, post card 1993 April 28, 1p 1993 May 5, post card 1993 May 25, post card 1993 June 1, card 1993 June 19,card 1993 July 12, card 1993 August 11, post card with photograph 1993 August 17, 2pps 1993 August 22, post card 1993 August 27, card 1993 September 15, 1p 1993 September 25, post card 1993 October 5, 1p and post card 1993 October 13, card 1993 October 15, post card 1993 November 21, post card 1993 December 25, ACS w/ envelope 1993 December 31, post card 1994 February 1, post card 1994 April 11, 1p 1994 April 18, 1p 1994 April 24, post card 1994 June 13, post card 1994 September 20, post card 1994 October 6, post card 1994 October 13, post card 1994 December 8, APS 1995 January 2, APS 1995 January 4, ACS w/ envelope, w/ poem "From Moss-Light to Hopper with Love" 1995 February 9, card 1995 March 23, post card 1995 April 9, APS 1995 May 13, ACS 1995 June 17, post card 1995 August 15/21, 2pps w/ 3pps of poetry and envelope; Poems: "In Another Life," "Elsewhere," "A Post card from Carthage" 1995 August 17, post card 1995 September 25, 3pps 1995 October 30, post card 1995 December 3, card 1995 December 8, post card 1996 July 1, post card w/ envelope 1996 May 9, card 1996 May 29, post card 1996 June 4, post card 1996 July 17, post card 1996 July 27, 1p w/ envelope 1996 October 5, 1p w/ card and envelope 1996 October 21, post card 1996 October 25, APS 1996, Christmas card 1997 May 13, 1p w/ envelope 1997 December 21, card 1998 June 11, 1p w/ envelope 1998 June 25, card w/ 2 pages of poetry and envelope; Poems: "Camellia" and "Sea-Bird" 1998 November 15, 2pps with post card, 3pps from "Irish Film Society" Newsletter, WERRC (Women's Education Research and Resource Centre) Conference Announcement and envelope 1998 December 18, Post It Note 1999 February 1, 1p 1999 February 4, 1p 1999 February 18, post card 1999 March 22, post card 1999 April 16, post card 1999 May 5, post card 1999 August 5, post card 1999 August 11, post card 1999 November 1, TLS, 1p 1999 December 28, ALS, 1p 2000 September 14, ALS, 1p w/ envelope 2000 September 27, ALS, 1p 2004 February 11, ACS 2004 August 20, TLS
MCCORMACK, W.J. / HUGH MAXTON (NOM DE PLUME) 1988 May 31, TLS, 1p
MORRISON, BLAKE 1992 June 3, 1p
MOTION, ANDREW 1981 January 5, post card 1981 May 8, post card 1982 March 4, 1p 1991 May 5, 1p w/ envelope 1997 December 17, 1p w/ envelope 2001 February 21, to Edna, 4pps w/ additional material 2004 February 27, email 2004 March 30, email
MULDOON, PAUL 1987 November 23, ALS, 2pps w/ envelope 1989 October 5, ANS w/ envelope 1991 April 6, ACS 1991 July 11, card 1992 February 10, ALS, 1p w/ envelope 1992 July 7, TC 1994 June 22, ALS, 1p w/ envelope 1994 August 17, ALS, 1p w/ envelope 1997 January, 1p 1998 January 27, 1p w/ envelope 1998 November 30, post card 1999 October 14, TLS, 1p w/ envelope 2001 March 30, printed invitation w/ envelope 2001 September 13, email 2003 31 August, email 2003, Christmas card 2004 December 13, Christmas card w/ envelope w/ poem "Twice on Clay" 2005 April 11, email 2005 May 5, email 2005 May 23, email 2005 June 2, email 2006 January 4, email 2006 February 24, TLS, 2pps w/envelope undated, ALS, 1p undated, ALS, 1p w/ envelope undated, ALS, 1p undated, ACS undated, ACS
NÍ CHUILLEANÁIN, EILÉAN 1987 July 2, ALS, 1p 1999 October 18, ALS, 1p [2000], ALS, 1p [2000], TLS, 1p 2001 August 20, ACS w/ envelope undated, ACS undated, TNS undated, 1p
NÍ DHOMHNAILL, NUALA 1986 February 21, ALS, 6pps 1986 May 16, ALS, 3pps 1986 June 5, ALS, 3pps 1986 December 11, ALS, 2pps 1986 December 20, ACS 1987 January 26, ALS, 4pps w/ envelope 1988 October 18, ACS with poems "An T-Aistriu Conaithe" and "Linn Na Gealaf," 1990 October 19, ACS w/ envelope 1990 November 18, ACS 1990 July 24, ACS 1995 January 4, APS undated, ACS undated, ACS undated, ACS undated, APS
O'DRISCOLL, DENNIS 1983 January 9, 1p 1993 March 3, TLS, 1p w/ enclosures: articles by DD, "At Work: Poet as Civil Servant" and "Circling the Square: A Thurles Prospect" 1993 April 9, ANS 1993 May 26, TLS, 1p 1993 May 28, ACS 1993 June 8, 2pps 1993 June 20, TLS, 2pps 1993 June 28, ACS 1993 June 29, TLS, 1p w/ review articles by DD of "Ginsberg: A Biography," and "The Poetry of Survival" 1993 July 22, TLS, 1p 1994 September 12, ACS 1994 December 6, APS 1995 August 24, 1p 1995, 1p w/ biographical sketch, and 3pp poetry; Poems, "Border Posts" and "Frames" 1996 January 31, 1p 1996 March 6, post card 1996 March 23, Post card 1996 September 22, 1p 1996 October 19, 1p 1998 October 22, post card 1999 February 9, 2pps 1999 February 27, postcard 1999 March 6, post card 2006 November 12, APS undated, ACS undated, 1p undated, card undated, ACS
O'GRADY, DESMOND 1989 February 22, ANS w/ 4pps poem "To John Montague at Sixty, February 1989”"
ORMSBY, FRANK 1974 September 8 [to Ciaran Carson], ALS, 2pps w/ poem "On Holiday" 1975 March 2, ALS, 1p w/ envelope
REID, CHRISTOPHER 1989 January 5, 1p
RICH, ADRIENNE 1986 June 3, 2pps 1994 June 13, APS w/ envelope 1994 August 19, TLS, 1p w/ envelope and part of poem "Inscriptions" 1995 July 9, 1p
ROBINSON, MARY, PRESIDENT OF IRELAND 1992 March 12, TNS 1993 April, ACS with envelope 1995 August 1, 1p 1996 December 9, 1p [MR to Liz Murphy]
SIMMONS, JAMES 1987 August 27, TNS 1991 January 15, ALS, 1p 1994 April 18, TLS, 1p w/ envelope 1994 November 27, TL [to Adrian] with ANS to McGuckian, 1p w/ envelope 1994 December 21, TLS [to Adrian] with ANS to McGuckian, 2pps w/ envelope undated, Christmas card undated, Christmas card
SIMMONS, JANICE 1994 October 10, 1p 1996 September 27, 1p 2004 September 24, TLS 2005 April 17, TLS
VENDLER, HELEN 1993 November 2, 1p [See Yeats Summer School Subject File] 1994 February 1, 4pps [See Yeats Summer School Subject File] 1994 August 27, ALS, 2pps w/ envelope [See Yeats Summer School Subject File]
WHEATLEY, DAVID 1995 December 29, 1p w/ envelope 1996 December 19, Christmas card 1997 May 19,1p 1998 June 3, 1p 2000 February 3, APS undated, 2pps